A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Historical Files, SG 1, Series 1 FA389
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Historical Files, SG 1, Series 1
1935-1981
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
FA389
39.6 Cubic Feet 90 boxes
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement note
The folders are arranged in alphabetical order by either institution or individual.
Biographical/Historical note
The Commonwealth Fund was established in 1918 with an endowment of $10 million from Mrs. Stephen V. Harkness for "benevolent, religious, educational and like purposes." The early grants supported a variety of programs while generally promoting welfare, especially child welfare. Several grants were made in the field of medical research, but the Board of Directors decided in 1920 that this field was already sufficiently supported by other philanthropic organizations.
Despite this decision, by the mid-1920s the chief interest of the Fund had become public health, including mental hygiene, community health, rural hospitals, medical research, and medical education. Other grant areas included war relief, educational and legal research, child welfare, and international medical fellowships.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IX; IV 4B 4
Scope and Contents note
The Commonwealth Fund office used these files as a cross reference system for the grants. The files concentrate from the 1950s to 1981. The folders consist of cross reference sheets and correspondence. There are some reports and photographs. Original boxes 317, 325, 326, 332, 333, 341, and 342 were not sent to the Archives; consequently files from D, E, P, and W are missing. Folders for The Johns Hopkins University and Massachusetts General Hospital are also missing.
Other Finding Aids note
Other available finding aids describing the Commonwealth Fund records include:
FA247 Commonwealth Fund Harkness House drawings
FA276 Commonwealth Fund records, Annual Reports, SG 1, Series 4
FA277 Commonwealth Fund records, Archives/Library, SG 1, Series 5
FA278 Commonwealth Fund records, Austrian Program, SG 1, Series 6
FA279 Commonwealth Fund records, Board of Directors, SG 1, Series 7
FA280 Commonwealth Fund records, Capital Grants, SG 1, Series 8
FA281 Commonwealth Fund records, Child Health Demonstrations, SG 1, Series 9
FA282 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Community Clinics, SG 1, Series 10
FA283 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Health Studies, SG 1, Series 11
FA284 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Public Health, SG 1, Series 12
FA285 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Publications, SG 1, Series 13
FA286 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Rural Hospitals, SG 1, Series 14
FA287 Commonwealth Fund records, Educational Research, SG 1, Series 15
FA288 Commonwealth Fund records, English Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 16
FA289 Commonwealth Fund records, Finance Committee, SG 1, Series 17
FA290 Commonwealth Fund records, Grants, SG 1, Series 18
FA291 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Family, SG 1, Series 19
FA292 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, SG 1, Series 20
FA428 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, Fellows Reports, SG 1, Series 20A
FA293 Commonwealth Fund records, Institute for Child Guidance, SG 1, Series 21
FA294 Commonwealth Fund records, Interface Program, SG 1, Series 22
FA295 Commonwealth Fund records, Legal Research Program, SG 1, Series 23
FA296 Commonwealth Fund records, Living at Home Program, SG 1, Series 24
FA297 Commonwealth Fund records, Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 25
FA298 Commonwealth Fund records, Miscellaneous - unprocessed
FA299 Commonwealth Fund records, Personnel - unprocessed
FA300 Commonwealth Fund records, Pilgrim Trust, SG 1, Series 28
FA301 Commonwealth Fund records, Program for the Prevention of Delinquency, SG 1, Series 29
FA302 Commonwealth Fund records, Reference Files, SG 1, Series 30
FA303 Commonwealth Fund records, Reports of the General Director, SG 1, Series 31
FA304 Commonwealth Fund records, Treasurer, SG 1, Series 32
FA305 Commonwealth Fund records, Turndown Lists, SG 1, Series 33 - unprocessed
FA306 Commonwealth Fund records, Vertical File (R. Fitz), SG 1, Series 34 - unprocessed
FA307 Commonwealth Fund records, Visual Materials, SG 1, Series 35
FA389 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Historical Files, SG 1, Series 1
FA390 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Officers Files, SG 1, Series 2
FA429 Commonwealth Fund records, President, Margaret E. Mahoney, SG 2, Series 1
FA430 Commonwealth Fund records, Book Program, SG 2, Series 2
Mental health; Medicine -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Medicine, Rural; Medical research; Medical education; Legal research; Legal issues; Child welfare; Education, Rural; Hygiene; Law; New York (State); New York (N.Y.); Child mental health; Child psychology; War relief; United States; Public welfare; Public health; Yale University; Social Science Research Council; Columbia University; Harvard University
- Cross Reference Sheets (Aa-Ac), September 5, 1951-November 18, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- A Better Chance (Boston, Massachusetts and New York, New York), January 18, 1971-September 30, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- University of Aberdeen, December 2, 1958-November 11, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Academy for Education Development, August 4, 1969-November 17, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Academy of Medicine - Institute of Chile, March 4-24, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Academy of Religion and Mental Health, January 24, 1956-January 4, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Ad), November 1, 1950-January 21, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Adelaide University, June 13, 1954-January 19, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Administrative Interoffice Memoranda, January 3, 1947-July 23, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Administrative Interoffice Memoranda, January 3, 1947-July 23, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Ae-Ak), February 5, 1952-October 2, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Affiliated Hospital Center, Inc. (Boston, Massachusetts), April 21, 1972-May 5, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Biographical/Historical note
  Brigham and Women's Hospital as of October 1, 1980.
- Africa, February 10, 1960-April 1, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- African American Institute, October 11, 1963-August 27, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- African Medical Research Foundation, April 7, 1975-June 30, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- African Student Aid Fund (New York), September 28, 1970-August 30, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Agency for International Development, July 1, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Ala-Ali), February 20, 1950-November 18, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- University of Alabama Press, November 17, 1975-December 9, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Alabama University, December 1, 1954-September 20, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Alameda County Medical Society, October 29, 1951-January 29, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Alaska Mental Health Enabling Act, September 2, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Alaska Methodist University, November 8, 1973-January 21, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Albany Medical College and Center Hospital, February 20, 1950-September 23, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- University of Alberta (Hospital), January 11, 1967-April 21, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Alcohol, April 16, 1976-March 19, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Aldrich, Herbert S., December 6, 1960-March 31, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Aldrich, Malcolm P., July 1, 1951-December 2, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Aldrich, Robert A., August 14. 1955-January 28, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Alexander, Dr. Philip (India), December 15, 1969-March 6, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Alfred University, October 30, 1972-January 21, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Alhambra Medical Clinic (Alex Gerber), May 22, 1967-July 19, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Alice Lloyd College, November 18, 1974-June 23, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Cross Reference Sheets (All), January 25, 1951-July 15, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Allen, Raymond B., October 3, 1969-September 13, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Almy, Thomas P. (Dartmouth Medical School - Department of Medicine), May 4, 1948-February 4, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Albert, Joel (Boston University - School of Medicine), January 28, 1970-February 1, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Alston, J. M., June 2, 1955-May 14, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Am-America), June 8, 1950-August 17, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Cross Reference Sheets - American (A-F), June 14, 1951-March 25, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- American Academy of Arts and Sciences, September 4, 1963-December 17, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- American Academy of General Practice, October 24, 1951-March 10, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- American Academy of Pediatrics (Pediatric Assistants), February 7, 1946-August 1, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- American Arbitration Association (Irving Ladimer and Robert Coulson), May 18, 1973-December 12, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- American Association for the Advancement of the Humanities, November 16, 1979-October 9, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- American Association for the Advancement of Science, January 3, 1957-February 13, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- American Association of Anatomists, June 6, 1949-December 20, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- American Association of Physicians and Social Scientists, November 29, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- American Association of State Colleges and Universities, September 18, 1973-October 7, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- American Association on Mental Deficiency, May 16, 1956-February 13, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- American Bar Association, March 5, 1975-September 29, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- American Board of Medical Specialities, July 19, 1972-April 14, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- American Board of Neurological Surgery (Kemp Clark), August 14, 1973-January 21, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- American Board of Psychiatry and Neurology, November 5, 1957-February 19, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 54)
- American Cancer Society, December 11, 1951-June 30, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 55)
- American Clinical and Climatological Associations (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania), July 8, 1974-September 11, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 56)
- American College Health Association (Evanston, Illinois), January 6, 1969-February 26, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 57)
- American College of Hospital Administration, January 27, 1958-January 16, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 58)
- American College of Legal Medicine, March 7, 1973-April 16, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 59)
- American College of Physicians, August 27, 1956-December 11, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 60)
- American College of Preventive Medicine, September 18, 1970-April 24, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 61)
- American Council of Learned Societies, November 8, 1977-February 22, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 62)
- American Council of Voluntary Agencies for Foreign Services, Inc. (Technical Assistance Information Clearing House), March 15, 1967-July 13, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 63)
- American Council on Education, October 31, 1955-June 22, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 64)
- American Doctor (California), March 27, 1969-April 8, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 65)
- American Federation for Clinical Research, February 19-27, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 66)
- American Foundation Studies, January 21, 1956-June 1, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 67)
- American Foundations Information Service, March 12, 1954-June 17, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 68)
- American Friends Service Committee, Inc. (Family Planning), May 6, 1969-April 10, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 69)
- Cross Reference Sheets - American (G-N), January 4, 1950-May 28, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 70)
- American Health Foundation, Decemer 16, 1971-March 15, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 71)
- American Humanics Foundation (Kansas City, Missouri), March 3, 1975-August 13, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 72)
- American Institute for Research, May 11-20, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 73)
- American Institute of Architects Task Force on Health Facilities Laboratory, January 12, 1971-June 21, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 74)
- American Medical Association (Accredition for Health Care in Jails), September 1, 1978-February 14, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 75)
- American Medical Association (Department of International Medicine), March 17, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 76)
- American Medical Association (Education and Research Foundation - Institute for Biomedical Research), August 27, 1969-May 1, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 77)
- American Medical Student Association, February 2, 1976-June 10, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 78)
- American Museum of Natural History, August 7, 1969-November 9, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 79)
- American Neurological Association, June 28, 1951-May 14, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 80)
- American Nurses Foundation, Inc. (Kansas City, Missouri), March 18, 1975-October 1, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 81)
- Cross Reference Sheets - American (O-Z), June 11, 1951-November 18, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 82)
- American Orthopsychiatric Association, November 11-25, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 83)
- American Psychiatric Association, August 13, 1974-March 27, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 84)
- American Psychoanalytic Association, November 10, 1954-December 2, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 85)
- American Psychological Association, October 12, 1951-December 10, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 86)
- American Public Health Association, September 10, 1951 to May 2, 1955; October 10, 1966 to October 7, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 87)
- American Public Health Association, September 10, 1951 to May 2, 1955; October 10, 1966 to October 7, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 88)
- American Red Cross, April 12, 1946-September 20, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 89)
- American Society of Internal Medicine (Computers), January 24, 1969-October 30, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 90)
- American University of Beirut, February 21, 1952-December 16, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 91)
- American University of Beirut, February 21, 1952-December 16, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 92)
- American University of Cairo, July 31, 1975-August 13, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 93)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Ames-Amu), May 16, 1950-June 16, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 94)
- Amherst College, June 4, 1964-February 4, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 95)
- Cross Reference Sheets (An-Anderson), October 20, 1935-December 9, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 96)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Andervont-Any), June 13, 1951-March 9, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 97)
- Anlyan, William G. (Duke University Medical Center), October 18, 1963-July 22, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 98)
- Antioch College, April 19, 1971-February 12, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 99)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Ap-Ar), April 28, 1950-December 17, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 100)
- Appalachian Regional Commission, October 26, 1971-November 19, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 101)
- Appalachian Regional Hospitals, February 14, 1970-January 11, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 102)
- Appleton-Century-Croft, December 9, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 103)
- Applied Resources, Inc. (Sean Sculley), February 14, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 104)
- Arizona Health Services Education Association, April 7, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 105)
- Arizona Medical Association, May 5, 1958-October 29, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 106)
- Arizona State College, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 107)
- University of Arizona (College of Medicine), October 25, 1972-July 13, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 108)
- University of Arkansas, May 2, 1951-September 5, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 109)
- Arlington Books, December 18, 1952-January 9, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 110)
- Arthritis and Rheumatism Foundation, September 14, 1951-December 15, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 111)
- Cross Reference Sheets (As), January 19, 1950-January 25, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 112)
- Asociacion Pro-Salud Maternal (Training and Research Center for Family Planning-Mexico), May 24, 1968-February 8, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 113)
- Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, January 27, 1971-June 26, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 114)
- Asper, Samuel (American College of Physicians), December 29, 1958-December 11, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 115)
- Associated Hospital Service of New York, July 27, 1944-September 6, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 116)
- Associated Medical Schools of Greater New York, March 6, 1973-November 3, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 117)
- Association for Academic Health Centers, December 20, 1971-August 22, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 118)
- Association for Rural Aid in Medicine, Inc. (Lalla Iverson), February 14, 1968-January 3, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 119)
- Association for the Advancement of Medical Instrumentation, March 22, 1966-April 24, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 120)
- Association for the Aid of Crippled Children, December 22, 1953-Setpember 29, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 121)
  Scope and Contents note
  Known as Foundation for Child Development as of September 26, 1972.
- Association for Voluntary Sterilization, Inc., June 25, 1973-March 10, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 122)
- Association of American Medical Colleges (Medical College Admissions Assessment Program - Student Handbook), December 5, 1967-August 3, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 123)
  Related Archival Materials note
  See Commonwealth Fund, Grant Series, Association of American Medical Colleges, Box 24, Folders 219-222.
- Association of American Medical Colleges (Medical College Admissions Assessment Program - Student Handbook), December 5, 1967-August 3, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 124)
- Association of American Medical Colleges (Medical College Admissions Assessment Program - Student Handbook), December 5, 1967-August 3, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 125)
- Association of Black Foundation Executives (Milfred C. Fierce), October 17, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 126)
- Association of Schools of Allied Health Professions, June 3, 1971-December 6, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 127)
  See Commonwealth Fund, Grant Series, National Commission on Accrediting, Boxes 223-224, Folders 2104-2114.
- Association of Schools of Allied Health Professions, February 9, 1970-January 25, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 128)
- Association on American Indian Affairs, October 11-13, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 129)
- Cross Reference Sheets (At), February 24, 1949-November 14, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 130)
- Atascadero (California) State Hospital, February 10, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 131)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Au-Az), June 4, 1951-March 30, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 132)
- University of Auckland (Hospital Medical School - Teaching Museum-Mortimer Kingsley), June 26, 1972-January 31, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 133)
  Mortimer Kingsley, Former Commonwealth Fund Harkness Fellow.
- Australia/New Zealand, January 12, 1981-November 6, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 134)
- Australia/New Zealand, January 12, 1981-November 6, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 135)
- Australian Association of Medical Schools, October 29, 1965-May 16, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 136)
- Australian College of General Practitioners, July 23, 1959-August 21, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 137)
- Australian National University, March 16, 1965-July 8, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 138)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Bab-Baj), September 11, 1951-June 21, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 139)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Bak-Bam), June 1, 1951-December 10, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 140)
- Balint, Michael, December 11, 1956-November 18, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 141)
- Ball State University, March 8, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 142)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Ban-Bar), January 17, 1951-June 4, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 143)
- Baptist Home (Columbia, Maryland), February 15, 1973-March 5, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 144)
- Barnett, Henry, L., April 12, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 145)
- Baruch Committee on Physical Medicine, January 31, 1944-April 29, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 146)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Bas-Bay), July 2, 1937-March 30, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 147)
- Basic Systems, Inc., June 6, 1961-October 16, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 148)
- Battelle Population Study Center (Seattle, Washington), April 13, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 149)
- Baylor College of Medicine (Texas Medical Center, Houston, Texas), December 12, 1955-February 21, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 150)
- Baylor College of Medicine/Rice University (Michael Debakey and Norman Hakerman), June 4, 1974-Novemer 8, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 151)
- Baylor University (Capital Grants), October 29, 1951-January 19, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 152)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Bea-Bem), July 27, 1946-December 17, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 153)
- Beeson, Paul B., April 23, 1976-May 10, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 154)
- Bellevue Hospital, March 17, 1966-March 18, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 155)
- Bellevue Ohio Area Historical Society, October 15, 1975-March 5, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 156)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Ben), May 26, 1950-December 1, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 157)
- Bennett, Ivan L., Jr., February 29, 1956-November 4, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 158)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Bera-Berre), December 2, 1948-May 15, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 159)
- Berkeley (California) Center for Human Interaction, December 28, 1970-August 18, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 160)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Berry), September 26, 1950-December 11, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 161)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Berryh-Bez), August 23, 1944-October 31, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 162)
- Beth Israel Hospital (Boston), October 23, 1953-January 13, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 163)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Bh-Bj), December 17, 1948-July 17, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 164)
- Bingham Association Fund, July 31, 1945-November 30, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 165)
- Bio-Research Institute, Inc. (Cambridge, Massachusetts), June 9, 1966-August 13, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 166)
- Bird, Remsen, November 10, 1952-August 9, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 167)
- Birdsall, William, October 24, 1950-December 7, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 168)
- Birmingham University, September 21, 1954-September 21, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 169)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Bl), December 18, 1950-March 30, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 170)
- Bloom, Samuel W., June 10, 1965-August 14, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 171)
- Blue Cross Association, June 20, 1968-May 1, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 172)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Boa-Boo), May 14, 1951-June 2, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 173)
- Bond, Douglass D. (University Hospitals Cleveland, Ohio), January 17, 1974-May 9, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 174)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Bor-Bot), January 22, 1951-March 27, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 175)
- Boston University, February 24, 1948-February 21, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 176)
- Boston University (Center for Law and Health Services), October 27, 1970-November 25, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 177)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Bou-Boy), February 23, 1950-November 7, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 178)
- Bowman Gray School of Medicine, October 16, 1959-April 15, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 179)
- Bowers, John Z., October 17, 1951-October 7, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 180)
- Boyd, Philip, August 4, 1971-September 2, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 181)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Bra), May 28, 1952-November 12, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 182)
- Brain Research Foundation, January 31, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 183)
- Brandeis University (School for Advanced Studies in Social Welfare - Florence Heller), January 12, 1959-September 28, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 184)
- Braunwald, Eugene (Peter Bent Brigham Hospital), April 2, 1974-November 20, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 185)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Bre), September 17, 1952-June 16, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 186)
- Breeze, William, September 15, 1966-November 1, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 187)
- Brennam, Troyen A. (Hertford College, Oxford, United Kingdom), May 12-24, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 188)
- Brenner, M. Harvey (Yale University, School of Medicine), July 9, 1971-August 9, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 189)
- Brewster, Kingman, Jr., June 27, 1966-November 9, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 190)
- Cross Reference Sheets (Bri), 1928-April 22, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 191)
- Brim, Orville G., Jr. (Body Rights), October 21, 1971-January 7, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 192)
- University of British Columbia, April 14, 1956-September 1, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 193)
- British Medical Journal (Rebecca Rainsbury), October 30, 1972-January 19, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 194)